[instrumental music]
Welcome to the 23rd annual
Westing Resort
best chef challenge.
[male #1]
'Don't burn those scallops.'
I'm Bertram Duesterberg,
your host.
'Our competing chefs
today are'
'first, from restaurant 182
in Sonoma..'
'The youngest winner ever of
the Schilling Palm d'cuisine'
Chef Hannah Diaz.
'From San Francisco,
where they host'
the acclaimed public
radio show two top
Chefs Arliss and
Julia St. Germain.
[indistinct chatter]
Jeff, do you want
the mousse?
- Jeff?
- Yeah, yeah.
Trained in Paris
he is executive chef
at La Petite Maison
Chef Adrien Ludo!
[indistinct chatter]
Where's my chives?
Let's go, people!
And first up
before our judges today..
Okay, let's move!
- Come on, go, go!
- 'Hurry up, people.'
Jeffrey Barge.
Thank you.
My..
[clears throat]
My first, dish today, is..
'...is, uh..'
[all screaming]
Oh, my goodness.
Call a doctor!
Is there a doctor
in house, please?
- Somebody call 9-1-1!
- Jeffrey!
[female #1]
'Jeffrey! Somebody!'
'Jeffrey, say something!'
'Can you hear me? Jeffrey?'
Doctor, he's not moving.
[indistinct radio chatter]
Anything from
the deputy coroner?
Just that he can't tell
us anything yet.
Tell him we need to know.
If this guy died of natural
causes we're going home.
- Why so grumpy?
- I'm not.
Why are we here? We don't
even know if it's a murder.
One of the chefs called
her daddy who's a state senator
who called the AG,
who called the assistant AG
who called me.
So we're here.
I hate politics.
This might go quick.
Victim had a fistfight
with the event organizer.
Happy days.
[Bertram]
I want to be very clear.
What happened was
sheerest accident.
I did nothing wrong.
Let's just stick to the facts,
Mr. Duesterberg.
You said you had a fight
with the victim. About what?
- Truffles.
- Truffles?
Yes. They, they're
very pricey fungus.
I know what a truffle is.
Uh, Jeffrey ordered a bundle
and he paid for them himself.
A few hours
before the competition
he couldn't find them.
He demanded replacements,
which would have cost thousands.
I said no. He started yelling
and then shoving.
Naturally, I defended myself.
Very gently, of course.
And then he, fell on his head?
Something like that?
It's as I said it wa..
It was an accident.
Oh, we'll see.
Jeffrey sounds like a scrapper.
Quick with his fists?
No, not really. He was..
He was a genius.
Genius can be noisy.
But he, he's never
laid hands on me before.
Genius, really?
Hmm.
[clears throat]
Hey, is he good for it?
Not sure yet. What's that?
I don't know. Some hors d'oeuvre
thing they're handing out.
- Want one?
- No, thanks.
I don't eat
anything I can't identify.
- Hmm.
- Excuse me.
Is this the victim's dish?
Yes.
Mmm.
Mm-hmm.
Excuse me.
[clears throat]
[grunting]
Pardon.
No genius there.
Waytoo much salt.
Hmm.
- Dr. Steiner.
- Hmm?
Long time.
New threads. Sharp.
Yes. The move from Sacramento
has been quite pleasant.
Fine wine, lovely weather,
no Patrick Jane
or so I hoped.
Cheeky.
Have you checked his mouth?
For a possible head injury?
I don't think so.
Don't be alarmed,
I amgoing to touch you.
Mr. Jane, please,
I am in the..
Yuck. Lisbon!
Excuse me.
What.. What made you think
to look there?
Well, bad-tasting food
means bad taste buds.
So much for the head wound.
[Patrick]
'Hmm.'
Duesterberg's off the hook.
He didn't die from a fall.
Let's huddle together,
divvy up the interviews.
What did kill him?
Poison.
[gags]
[theme music]
Preliminary test came back.
Deputy Coroner says that
the poison is probably ricin.
Victim either
ate it or drank it.
It makes sense.
If it was airborne
people would be dropping
like flies.
Ricin's easy enough to make.
Grind up some castor beans.
Makes for a broad suspect pool.
They tested the victim's food
there's no sign of it there
or in the kitchen.
The ricin takes hours to work.
Must've been something
he ingested a while ago.
No need to get
your stomach pumped then, huh?
[phone ringing]
Ha, funny.
You search the room. Test any
liquid or food that you find.
Yeah, okay.
Thanks. The victim's wife
just arrived.
I'll handle it.
You talk to the other chefs.
Duesterberg says that
the winner of the contest
gets 100 grand.
[Teresa]
'What are you doing?'
Oh, um..
Trying to get the taste
of salty food out of my mouth.
Pot de creme. It's basically
a pretentious chocolate pudding.
- Very nice. You want some?
- No.
We have to go and talk
to the victim's wife.
Mmm. Well, maybe
she'll want some.
Comfort food.
[Arliss]
'Jeffrey was a dear friend.'
We'd known each other for years.
Which is why I had
my father bring you on.
We want to find out
who did this.
Interesting that
you called us in
before anyone knew
it was poison.
You know something
everyone else didn't?
No, I just knew
that something was wrong.
Now you're all in competition
for a large cash prize.
Helps that one of you is dead,
doesn't it?
- 'Helps?'
- We eat together.
We work together.
We're comrades.
[Diaz chuckles]
Something to add,
Ms. Diaz?
Dude, if we're all
such comrades
why'd you try and steal
Jeff's sous-chef?
Not true.
Inquiries were made,
that's all.
[chuckles]
Yeah, right.
How'd you feel
about the victim?
I hated his guts.
Egotistical, manipulative
maybe half as good
as he thought he was.
Which would still make him
twice the chef that you are.
Why don't you go
get another tattoo?
Bite me, Julia.
The delivery guy says
he left Jeffrey's truffles
on his station this morning,
then they vanished.
So who stole the truffles?
[French accent]
Well, stealing truffles
makes one of us a murderer?
It's a start.
[scoffs]
What?
That is exactly the kind
of thing that hewould do.
He and Jeffrey
never really got along.
You fat bastard.
And truffles are
very expensive, aren't they?
And you wouldn't
throw them out.
Where does he keep his food?
Down on the left side
of the pantry.
You know who would stop
at nothing to win? Those two.
Ask them about the book deal
they've been chasing.
'A competition prize
would help that, no?'
[clears throat]
Okay, fine. Arrest me.
But I didn't
steal the truffles, okay?
I rescued them
from a terrible, terrible fate.
I see.
Did Jeffrey have any problems
that you knew about
personally or at work?
[sighs]
Well, um..
We were a problem.
We're separated.
I haven't spoken
to Jeffrey in months.
What was the breakup about?
Oh, god, what wasn't? Um..
Drinking, mostly.
Occupational disease
for chefs.
It's the pressure.
It wants a release.
That, and, um..
Don't listen to her,
whatever she says.
She hates Jeff.
- And you are?
- Victim's brother.
Cheekbones.
Come on. You can see that.
[mouthing]
Uh, Kevin,
why don't we talk later?
Yeah, I-I don't think so,
Abigail.
My brother was
a freakin' genius, alright?
You think anybody in my family
taught him how to cook?
Please. He wanted to be a great
chef, and that's what he was.
Did it all by himself.
And you?
You were perfectly happy
to spend his money
weren't you, Abigail?
Your brother was a great man.
He elevated himself, didn't he?
But you didn't.
That must've been cause for
some friction, I would think.
'Did he leave you anything,
your brother?'
Or did he leave it all
to the hated sister-in-law?
- The money, the restaurant--
- Why don't you step back?
Kevin, that's enough, alright?
No, you don't tell me
what to do, okay?
As you can see, drinking,
it runs in the family.
[Kevin]
'Oh, s-see, that's how wrong
you are, actually.'
Jeff was sober. He was
in the program for two weeks.
Right. I've heard that before.
It's probably why he called.
You said
you hadn't talked to him.
I-I didn't talk.
Whoa. Two weeks sober.
That's impressive.
And what else
are you hiding from us?
Look, he called last night
at 12:30.
I hung up.
What'd he say?
He said..
[sighs]
He said he was sorry.
[knocks on door]
[Wayne]
'Hey.'
Test for ricin.
Yellow means positive,
nothing means..
[sighs]
...nothing.
This place is quite a mess.
What do you think
the intruder wanted?
Nobody was looking
for anything.
Jeffrey did this himself.
And you know this, how?
The punched-in mirror
is an act of self-hatred.
Plus, all these drawers
are closed.
A thoughtful ransacker
would close maybe one
but all of them? No.
Anyway.. Room's cleared.
No poison. We're moving on.
[Patrick]
'That's nice.'
Except you're not.
What's up?
Well, Jeffrey
was recently sober
but acting erratically.
Demolishing his room,
picking fistfights
calling his estranged wife
in the middle of the night
you know what that's called?
Relapse?
Yes. And an addict on a relapse
will hide his stash.
Ah.
[chuckles]
What better way
to poison a drunk
than through his drink?
Let's check it out.
'Let's.'
There we go.
Hold the applause.
Bingo.
[Patrick]
'Poison gin.'
A smart way
to eliminate a rival.
But not the act
of a gentleman, is it?
[imitates French accent]
MonsieurLudo?
Are you joking?
Rigsby, take him in.
[Ludo]
'This is not right.'
I have done nothing.
- Hang on.
- Come on, let's..
[Patrick]
'She's the one
we need to talk to.'
Me? Wh..
You should've seen your reaction
when I accused Ludo..
Pure relief.
Oh, come on, please.
At least attempt denying it.
- I didn't do it.
- She's the one.
[Hannah sighs]
Thank you.
Merci.
Why would I want
to kill Jeffrey?
Winning a contest like this
would do a lot for a young woman
trying to prove herself.
I don't have anything
to prove.
'You're a good cook.'
Making ricin out of castor beans
wouldn't be hard, would it?
No. But I didn't.
[Kimball]
Take a look at this, Hanna.
That's your credit card
statement.
You bought gin.
I'm over 21,
it's not a crime.
[Kimball]
'You just happened to buy
yourself the same type of gin'
'we found in the victim's room?'
Look, can I go
or what? I..
Hannah.
We have enough to charge
you with murder right now.
You need to talk to us,
tell us your side of the story.
[sighs]
I'm 28.
I run my own kitchen.
I don't have any..
Food channel connections
no cookbook
with my name on it.
The Westing is my way up.
[scoffs]
Jeffrey was the one to beat.
We all knew it.
So I figured,
get him a drink.
Why not?
Level the playing field.
So, yeah,
I bought him the gin.
But I have no idea
how the ricin got in there.
Okay.
I just tried
to get him drunk, that's all.
No poison.
[sighs]
Without anything else,
we can't hold her.
What do you got?
Jeffrey's phone records.
Confirmed the call
with his wife.
How long did they talk?
'About five seconds.
Guess she did hang up.'
But there's a second call
at 2:00 a.m.
That one lasted
over an hour.
- Who'd he call?
- His restaurant.
Ms. Barge,
you have a minute?
Yeah, sure. What's up?
- Money troubles?
- How'd you guess?
Well, it's a restaurant.
They always have money troubles.
Well, this restaurant's
drowning in debt.
Jeffrey was driving this place
off a cliff.
It was all about the food.
This is Eliza Greene,
Jeffrey's sous-chef.
She's keeping things afloat
while I get my bearings..
now that I own
a failing restaurant.
[Eliza chuckles]
Oh, sorry.
Um, people would say that
the place is failing
and, uh, Jeffrey would say
yes, but failing
with style.
Eliza, oh, you're the one
the others wanted to hire.
You must be very good.
I guess. I wouldn't know.
False modesty?
Jeffrey called the restaurant
last night at 2:00 a.m.
Do you know
who he spoke to?
Me. Oh, uh, he was considering
changing the menu
for the contest,
wanted to talk about it.
Couldn't that have waited
till the morning?
That was just Jeff
being Jeff.
He was always
after perfection.
Irritating, getting
a phone call like that
when you're on your way home
from work, isn't it?
Not at all.
If you want
to make something great
that's the job.
[clears throat]
You know you should really
get these, uh, deposits posted
or the checks are gonna bounce.
Thanks for your time.
- 'Thank you.'
- Night.
Bye.
- Bye.
Where are my keys?
You picked my pocket?
- My turn to drive.
- Jane!
Oh, don't be
such an old lady. Get in.
Your fears are groundless.
You're right.
The car has air bags.
[grunting]
[screaming]
Oh, no.
Oh, bad move.
[grunting]
[groaning]
[crickets chirping]
[Patrick]
'Oh.'
[Teresa]
'Victim's brother?'
[Patrick]
'Kevin.'
Oh, I can't tell you how happy
I am that wasn't my car.
You're out
of your freakin' mind.
I would never, ever
harm my brother, ever.
You assaulted
and robbed a girl, Kevin
who ran your brother's
restaurant.
You don't think that makes
you a little suspicious?
That had nothing to do
with what happened to Jeff.
I don't believe you.
I can tell you why I went
after the money, alright
but I'm gonna need
some guarantees.
Oh, so we're negotiating now,
are we?
I have valuable information.
I can help you solve
Jeff's murder.
But you're not
gonna tell us anything
unless we cut you a deal?
We're talking about
your brother here, Kevin.
That's pretty low.
You know what?
You're going to jail.
You'll have plenty of time
to think about
how you could've
done things differently.
Wait.
Sean Horlick.
Jeff owed him money.
He needed it
for the restaurant.
Guy's a loan shark.
I actually put them in touch
five months ago.
I get a call yesterday
from Horlick
and he says unless I want
to end up like Jeff
I'd better get him
the money he owed.
So you rob
your dead brother's wife?
[scoffs]
She was always trying
to turn Jeff against me.
Said I was a bad influence
or somethin'.
Imagine that, huh?
Crazy.
[sighs]
I knew their deposit schedule
and they don't keep a gun.
I figured
she screwed me before
I screw her back.
Sean Horlick.
What else do you know
about him?
Fraud, racketeering, extortion,
couple of violent crimes
sprinkled in.
Charges never seem to stick.
Horlick's smart.
Track him down.
Take Rigsby.
Okay.
Cho, look into
Jeffrey's restaurant
the financial records,
see who else he owed money to.
[yawning]
I'll come with.
I'm a mite peckish.
What does thatmean?
It means I'm hungry.
- I can't read this.
- No?
Oh, that says,
"March '09 accounts payable."
- Oh!
- Hmm?
This, this is just ridiculous.
This is delicious.
[laughing]
Thank you.
Let's hope you can keep
the quality up
with the new boss.
Abigail seems more concerned
about the money than the menu.
Won't be a problem, I promise.
For God's sake.
Did you try this?
You don't like Abigail much,
do you?
- 'Well.'
- Do it over.
You're obviously
very talented.
You should've struck out
on your own a long time ago
unless there was
some reason to stay.
I didtry to strike out
on my own, actually
couple months ago.
- Failed with style?
- 'I wish.'
State wouldn't
grant me my liquor license.
[chuckles]
No license,
no investors, so..
'Luckily, Jeffrey
took me back again.'
So why not hook up
with him?
He was separated,
available.
[chuckles]
I've never liked
waiting in lines.
Excuse me.
I've got prep work to do.
- Thanks for lunch.
- Uh-huh.
'I didn't see any other loans on
the books. It's a good thing.'
Jeffrey wasn't even taking
a salary the last few months.
He wasn't? Hmm.
We're gonna have to
make a stop on the way back.
[Wayne sighs]
Huh. Magic brownies.
This is more...clean-cut
than I'd expected.
Yeah, medical pot,
it's a growth industry.
[Josh]
'First timers, huh?'
I'll tell you the same thing
I tell all the newbies.
go for today's specials.
Sure, they're
a couple bucks more
but between you and me
and the wall
it's the freshest herb we got.
Plus it's locally grown.
Who doesn't wanna support
local farmers?
CBI. Where's your boss?
Uh, Mr. Horlick?
I couldn't say.
But, uh, our permits are all
up to date by the book, 100%.
Well, Mr. Horlick's a suspect
in a murder investigation, Josh
so you if you know where he is,
you should tell us right now.
Is, uh, there a problem here?
We're here about
Jeffrey Barge.
Who? Oh. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, Jeff. Sure.
Sure. What about him?
Jeffrey died yesterday.
Yeah. Yeah, I know. I saw that
on the news. Wow. Heavy.
I mean, boom, he's here.
He's gone.
And how about that?
Life, huh?
We know you lent him money,
Mr. Horlick.
Well, how do you know that?
I mean, who says?
I'll take that as a yes.
Frosty one, aren't we?
I like it.
You like jail, too?
Yeah, that's right.
Kevin told us everything.
It's about time
you did as well.
Fine.
I called him
about the money.
Obviously, he drew some sinister
and incorrect implications
from our conversation
but it was all
a big misunderstanding.
Chalk it up to my,
my poor communication skills.
I think you communicate
very well.
Yes, you do.
You have sleazebag
written across your forehead
in big letters.
Why would I kill Jeff?
You don't off someone
who can pay you back.
I mean, the guy practically
lived at the Ritz.
What are you talking about?
Jeff was broke.
Yeah, that's what he wanted me
to think, too.
But I got a buddy who works
security at the hotel.
He saw the deadbeat
staying there a bunch of times.
You don't stay there unless
your pockets are padded.
I'd like to take yousometime,
thaw you out a little bit.
Yeah, that'll happen.
We got something.
Jeffrey stayed at the Ritz
over a dozen times
in the past two months,
paid in cash every time.
Looks like an affair.
But Jeffrey and his wife
lived separate lives.
Why would he care
if there was a record of it?
Maybe his partner cared.
Because she's married.
She had the money.
She paid for the room
but she paid in cash so
her husband wouldn't find out.
Keep digging.
Find out who the woman was.
[indistinct chatter]
Mmm. Next round's
tomorrow, huh?
Keep workin'.
You'll get there.
Merci beaucoup.
Arliss.
[Patrick]
'Careful, careful.'
Oh, that smells good.
What is that?
Knock yourself out.
It's not for the competition.
It's my lunch.
I'd advise against that.
Don't listen to him.
He's a coward.
- Is he?
- It's the Red Savina pepper.
- It's kinda spicy.
- 'Kind of?'
It's the hottest pepper
known to man. Trust me.
Leave it alone.
It's good on everything
meat, fruit, soups.
Not that any of the people
would know. Babies.
Well, I'd love a little try
of that. Thank you.
Mr. Jane,
our chefs are extremely busy.
Would you mind coming back
another time?
You're quite the ghoul,
aren't you, Duesterberg?
Dragging on
this meaningless contest
after a man
has been killed.
This contest, Mr. Jane,
is an affirmation of life.
It's a testament that
appetite still exists
even in the face of death.
And you need the money.
- Time for you to go.
- Fine.
I have all the information
I need, thank you very much.
He lies. He hasn't asked
one single question.
Why would I? I can learn
everything I need to learn
from watching you all cook.
You, for example,
use lemon to the point
of excess.
'Tart, aggressive flavors,
sublimated aggression'
'toward an important figure
in your life.'
Obviously,
you're a daddy's girl
so I'm gonna go
with mother.
No, let me correct that..
'...stepmother.'
'Ludo!'
You were adopted, no?
No. I wasn't.
Took a shot. Moving on.
You were having an affair
with Jeffrey.
'Weren't you?'
What?
You can tell all this
by the food?
[Patrick]
'Well, they cooked together
every day'
yet their kitchen
rhythms are off.
They're bashing into each other,
getting in each other's way.
You're not paying enough
attention to her, Arliss.
No wonder she strayed.
That's nonsense.
Really? Then why did
your wife have her father put
the state's best police force
on this case?
Look at her, Arliss.
'She's made no attempt'
no attempt at all
to deny it.
Is it true?
- I..
- So I take it you know
about Julia's affair
with the victim now.
Oh, roger that.
Jeff and I got together
about five months ago
after he separated
from his wife.
[Patrick]
'But he ended it.'
Yes.
When?
The night before he died.
'I went to his room
at the resort.'
'He was drunk. I thought
he was trying to get sober'
but I guess
not that night.
Jeff didn't
handle stress well.
Must have made you angry.
No. I accepted it.
I loved him.
But he was a drunk.
Better left alone.
Wise of you.
I asked for a glass
of water.
I'm sure it'll be here
in a minute.
You think I'm entitled
and snippy and rich.
My father's a senator.
I don't have to take crap
from people like you.
I'm just trying to figure out
who killed Jeffrey Barge,
that's all.
I didn't kill him.
I don't believe you, Julia,
not yet.
[sighs]
I really need
that glass of water.
I'll get it.
We still have a few more
questions for you.
[Patrick]
'Lisbon!'
9-1-1.
Julia? Julia?
Julia. Can you hear me?
Are you on medication?
Come on. Answer.
How many fingers
am I holding up?
'Julia!'
[Teresa]
Yes. Uh-huh.
I know. Yes.
Mr. Attorney General, sir,
I.. I-I understand completely.
I will.
She's straightening.
Straightening her desk.
Uh-oh.
Absolutely.
Coroner's office
says it was ricin poisoning
uh, just like Jeffrey.
Guess they were both
poisoned at the hotel.
Oh, crap.
Is she straightening?
Victim was a senator's daughter.
AG must be livid.
Ugh. It's not our fault.
Ricin takes hours to kick in.
[Wayne]
'Yeah, tell it to the AG.'
[sighs]
What's going on
with the search?
Local sheriff's working on it
taking every food and liquid
off the resort to be tested.
Resort, the contest,
it's all been shut down.
News flash. The AG wants
this case closed now.
Well, we've got
two dead married lovers.
I'd say the killer's a spouse.
Let's start with that.
[Kimball]
There he is.
Cinnamon,
sage and coriander
a squeeze of lemon,
then butter.
No, no garlic.
Not at all. Ciao.
Idiot.
Your wife just died, and you're
talking about recipes?
What would you have me do?
Sir, we'd like to discuss
your wife's estate.
Yes. Sorry.
Idiots. Garlic.
So Julia had money.
So what?
Well, you stand to inherit
all of it, isn't that right?
Yes. So?
Your wife and her lover
are now both dead
killed the same way. That makes
you our number one guy.
Or number two, I'd say.
Have you talked to Abigail yet?
[Wayne]
'Why?'
Ask her about the fight
she and Jeffrey had
at the Fairplex Market
two weeks ago.
It was quite a scene.
You didn't think
to mention this earlier?
Interrogation focuses the mind.
What can I say?
Except you're lying.
Jeffrey hadn't seen his wife
in months.
If Abigail said that,
she'sthe liar.
The market clerk
confirmed the story.
You were in contact with Jeff,
and you were fighting.
Look, I did not kill Jeffrey
if that's what
you're getting at.
'I didn't even know
about this thing with Julia.'
What were you fighting about?
You've really changed
your look, Abigail.
'Haven't you?'
Not that you don't
look lovely now.
It's just this old look, uh,
accentuated your assets.
My husband just died, okay?
You're still putting in time
with the make-up though, I see.
So appearance is important
to you.
What are you getting at?
She's put on 5 or 6 pounds
doesn't fit into
the sleek outfits anymore
so she wears this.
She's pregnant. Right?
'Congratulations.
First trimester.'
Jeff's child, right?
[sighs]
Right?
A few months ago, he came by
to pick up some stuff.
Things happened.
And two weeks ago,
I took a pregnancy test.
How did he take the news
of impending fatherhood?
Okay.
That's what you were
fighting about.
I don't know why
I didn't tell you.
I've been, uh..
...confused.
My parents don't even know.
[sighs]
Do us a favor, Abigail.
We're gonna need to search
your house.
Save us all some time
and grant us permission.
[birds chirping]
Did you know
a full-grown elephant
can eat up to 495 pounds
of food per day?
Could you at least
pretend to be helping?
Got somethin'.
Found this in the garage.
Nice work.
And we care about
a bag of beans why?
Castor beans.
They're used to make ricin.
Ah, of course.
Naughty Abigail.
We found traces of ricin
in Julia's favorite red pepper.
Her death was not accidental.
Both her and your husband
were specifically targeted.
Together with the castor
beans we found
it's not looking good for you.
My client denies any involvement
in these killings.
She bore no malice
towards her husband
or Ms. St. Germain.
No malice
toward her alcoholic
and fiscally irresponsible
husband and his lover?
'She was not aware
of that relationship'
nor did she ever set foot
in that resort.
- Which you can't prove.
- I didn't do this..
Then how do you explain
the castor beans in your house?
She had no knowledge of them.
That's convenient.
This is a grieving widow,
a pregnant, grieving widow.
'You think that a jury
is going to convict'
on this circumstantial Traif?
We can make this stick,
and you know it.
Believe me, you will feel
much better if you..
[phone ringing]
Would you excuse me?
What?
- What emergency?
- Follow me.
Jane, I don't really
have time for this.
I was working on getting
a confession.
- This is far more important.
- What is?
Agents, welcome.
It's such a relief to know
that the killer
has been caught.
Just doing our job.
And thank you for coming to
this little memorial dinner.
Dinner?
Honoring Jeffrey and Julia.
We're having dinner?
Gotta eat.
I certainly hope
you enjoy yourself.
It should be delicious.
Excuse me.
Those serviettes
are horrifying.
You have five seconds
to tell me what's going on.
First, we need a drink.
Is it that bad?
It's lovely.
- '...finely chopped.'
- 'We're gonna need more soup.'
Not bad, Ludo.
Can we get
the bowls ready?
You shouldn't be here.
Yeah, you're probably right.
You gonna make me leave?
I hope not.
Excuse me.
Oh, excuse me.
I thought you'd be
a little more grateful.
I did just catch
your friend's killer.
We're grateful.
Just a little busy.
Is that it?
- Oh, that smells great.
- Not now, s'il vous plait.
Okay, okay.
Oh, oops! Whoa! Oops!
Fire! Fire! Fire!
Quick! Aah!
Whoa! Ah!
You know, I-I'm just gonna
leave you guys with that.
Aah!
Alright, everyone, please.
Lift your glass.
To Jeffrey and Julia,
friends, colleagues
titans in the culinary world
'you will not be
soon forgotten.'
- Salud.
- Cheers.
Ahh.
Mm-hmm.
To begin,
we have a melon soup
'Prosciutto di Parma,
mint and basil.'
Mmm.
A reinterpretation
of one of Julia's specialties.
Bon appetite.
Thank you.
Come on. Don't let
your Midwestern taste buds
'hold you back.'
[coughing]
Oh, chef.
- What is this spice?
- 'Spice?'
[coughing]
I like a little heat,
but this is overpowering.
Whoa.
We didn't add any heat.
Whew! That would be me.
Sorry.
Fire! Fire!
The Red Savina pepper
ah, I got it
from Julia's pantry.
I thought
it would be appropriate
'and I'm just mad
for heat, so..'
'Obviously, I was
a little heavy-handed.'
My-my apologies.
What's the trouble, Eliza?
I don't, um..
I don't feel well.
I should go.
What's the problem?
[Eliza]
'Uh, the peppers,
it didn't go down well.'
The pepper?
What's wrong with the pepper?
If you don't wanna talk
about it here
we can take it down
to headquarters.
How long can we keep her there?
48 hours.
Wow, that's a stretch of time.
I have to leave.
I have to leave right now.
[Patrick]
'No, that would
be rude. I don't think so.'
What is wrong with you?
We all have to go
to the hospital right now.
[Teresa]
'What for?'
The pepper...I think
it was poisoned.
I-I-I saw Ludo put
something into it.
I did not. How dare you!
Maybe you're just cramping
a little? Just a little--
Alright, alright.
I poisoned Julia's pepper.
And Jeffrey's gin.
Yes, yes! Just bring me
to a hospital.
No, hospitals
are terrible germ factories.
- 'You don't wanna go there.'
- Are you insane?
Relax. We knew about the ricin
in the pepper.
We just didn't know
who put it there.
I don't understand.
Are we poisoned?
No. I switched the peppers.
[all sighs]
Clever of me.
[whispering]
God.
[sighs]
Okay, so we know that your
restaurant didn't fail, Eliza.
Jeffrey and Julia,
they killed it.
We did some digging
on Julia's father.
He's the one who squashed
your liquor license.
Jeffrey was a drunk.
He needed you in his kitchen,
so he asked his lover
if she could have her big,
powerful daddy do her a favor.
He didn't call you that night to talk about recipes, did he?
He called to apologize for sabotaging your liquor license,
for ruining any chance you had at opening your own place.
But I..
I am trying to become
a better man.
I am.
He told you what he did
and then you,
decided to take your revenge.
So you got some castor beans,
mixed up a batch of ricin
and went to the resort
to find him.
Yeah.
[scoffs]
I went to his room.
[knock on door]
Oh, Jeff.
I accept your apology.
Let me just, wash up.
[Eliza]
He was such a fool.
Like I was gonna let that go?
Like we were just gonna make up and all be friends again?
That's just...ridiculous.
[Teresa]
And then you
went to the pantry
and, uh, you found
Julia's pepper
and you dosed that, too.
One time I was cleaning shrimp
for Jeffrey.
There were, like,
40 pounds of it
and it was still half frozen,
but that was the job.
'I couldn't feel my hands.
It was so cold.'
I realized I was cutting
the flesh off my own fingers.
Carving it off.
And I didn't mind
because Jeffrey
had a vision.
I had a vision.
And he said, go, babe.
You deserve your own place.
But he was lying.
Him and his..
...rich bitch girlfriend.
Like I was gonna
let that go.
He said, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry?
What good is that?
[Abigail]
'Agent Lisbon, a word.'
- How can I help you?
- You framed me.
You put those castor beans
in my house, didn't you?
Ma'am, on my word of honor
I did not know that
those beans were planted.
Mr. Jane was responsible.
I should've known.
I should've stopped him,
and I didn't
and for that,
I am really sorry.
Why?
He thought in order to catch
the killer
that somebody else had to be
suspected of the crime.
He's probably right.
I know you must be angry.
[sighs]
Trying to leave
the anger behind.
Though that's pretty much
impossible, isn't it?
It's hard.
[sighs]
Anyway, thank you
for being honest with me.
Tell Mr. Jane he's
a mean, irresponsible sadist.
'Oh, I will.'
Ms. Barge?
Living with an alcoholic
is hard.
Some never change.
They don't even want to.
But your husband checked
into treatment two weeks ago
right after you told him
about the baby.
I think he wanted to be there
for you and your child.
That's why he ended
the relationship with Julia.
For what it's worth, it seemed
like he wanted to change.
Thank you.
[dramatic music]
It's okay. She's gone.
- Who's gone?
- 'Oh, please.'
Your guilty conscience
is obvious and well deserved.
Meh. Justice can be
a harsh mistress.
Omelets and eggs,
ends to means
all's well that ends well.
A glib answer's no excuse.
Oh, and Abigail said
to tell you
that you are
a mean, irresponsible sadist.
Well, that's pretty accurate.
'You okay?'
No point denying it to me.
I'm fine.
Okay.
Goodnight.
[instrumental music]
[Patrick]
Stay tuned for scenes
from our next episode.
[theme music]